Okay, so sometimes you want to store
multiple pieces of information and you
may be thinking, well, how do I do that?
Maybe you want to store multiple
information pieces of information about
multiple things. So for example, here I
have an array of numbers which is 4 5 6
1 2 3. Perhaps I want to store the name
of the movie that's associated with
them. So if these are the episodes in
Star Wars, then episode 4 I would want
to store a new hope as the name and um
episode 5 I'd want to store the Empire
Strikes Back, etc., etc. Um one of the
ways you can do that is with a parallel
array. So what a parallel array means is
that you keep your information in the
same position in every single array. So
in other words, position Z holds four in
the numbers array. position zero holds
um a new hope because a new hope is
associated with the number four. Uh the
Empire Strikes Back would be in the one
position and that is associated with the
five because the five is also in the one
position of this array. So in other
words, because the positions of the
arrays line up, you can use the
positioning where it sits in the array
to figure out extra information about
it. So now I know that if I go to the
last position, Revenge of the Sith, the
last position of the names array is
going to correspond with the last
position of the numbers array. Meaning
three corresponds with Revenge of the
Sith. And we could keep storing
additional information this way. So I
could say let has storm troopers equal.
And then a new hope does have
stormtroopers. So we'd store true. Uh
the Empire Strikes Back does, so we'd
store true.
Um,
wow, I'm blanking. Return of the Jedi
does, so we'd store true. Um, Phantom
Menace does not, so we'd store false.
Uh, Attack of the Clones does not, so
we'd store false. Uh, you could debate
with me on whether or not the clones
count as Stormtroopers in Revenge of the
Sith, but we're going to store false
just for the sake of simplicity. So now,
if I look through my three parallel
arrays, I am now storing three pieces of
information about a single movie. So,
for example, a new hope I now know is
episode 4 and it has stormtroopers. The
Empire Strikes Back is Empire. Good
luck. The Empire Strikes Back is episode
5 and it also has stormtroopers. And
because all of the arrays are in the
same positioning because all the
information is organized in the exact
same order. We call these parallel
arrays. There's a small weakness with
parallel arrays and that is that they're
not actually glued together. So, for
example, if I were to uncomment this
bubble sort that we just built, um, and
I were to sort numbers, suddenly this
would now be 1 2 3 4 5 6. Now, it would
be saying that A New Hope is episode 1
and that it has Stormtroopers. Um, and
so now our information is broken and
worthless. Broken information is
worthless. So, um,
what we'd want to do is if we sort one
of these arrays, we'd want to sort all
of the arrays. And that can be a pain.
And so, we're not going to cover that at
this point in time. You would just take
this same logic and you would expand on
it. And if you want to do that, go ahead
and ask Chad GBT how to expand the
bubble sort logic to do three arrays.
Um, but
there are much better sorting methods,
and we'll learn those in a minute. But
for now, I would just want you to know
that if you want to store multiple
pieces of information and you need them
all to stay associated, one thing you
could do is you could use parallel
arrays and store the information
parallel to another array. All right,
thanks for watching.